WILLIAMS AJAYI BALOGUN

Frontend Developer

https://williamsbalogun.netlify.app

th https://linkedin.com/in/williamsbalogun

https://github.com/willhemz

https://twitter.com/king_hayjhay?t=NQhyW25e51IwiPa1lOcC1g&s=09

⊠ williamsbalogun49@gmail.com

Q Lagos, Nigeria.

SUMMARY

Experienced Frontend Developer with proficiency in utilizing high end stacks in creating quality websites and web applications. Open-source contributor, facilitator, not shy of tough tasks, ably solid in engaging and collaborating with other developers, designers, product managers.

EDUCATION

Obafemi Awolowo University

2016 - 2022

B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering (CGPA 4.03/5.00)

Class Rank: Top 10%

Undergraduate Research – "Numerical Study on the Heat Transfer Enhancement in Straight and Wavy Microchannel Heat Sinks Under Pulsating CuO-Al2O3/H2O Hybrid Nanofluid"

EXPERIENCE

HNG Frontend Intern at Zuri

October – December (2022)

- Collaborated with several Developers (Frontend, Backend), DevOps, Designers and Product Manager to building web solutions to problems. Most notable are:
 - https://coverly.app
 - https://streetrates.info

Freelance Developer

2020 - 2022

- Worked with several clients and developers in building, modifying and restructuring their web sites and web applications.

- Volunteered and collaborated in the development of a shopping websites for a startup company (https://umecarts.com)
- Volunteered and collaborated in the development of a website containing designs catalogs for Delta Computers & Stores Ltd (https://newdcstech.com)

Staff 2012 – 2016

- Worked in the training department to tutor trainees on the use of Microsoft Office Applications and also helped them boost their typing skills.
- Was Head of Training in 2013 through 2014. Managed trainees' welfare.
- Worked in the operations department as a Graphics Designer. Created designs (booklets, magazines, logo, ID cards, complementary cards, calendars, shirt designs etc.) for individuals, brands, schools, organizations and government bodies etc.
- Was Head of Operations in 2015. Managed all jobs from our clients and ensured tasks are duly assigned and deadlines were met. Ensured clients got satisfaction from jobs delivered.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScriptTypeScriptjQueryReact

Redux
Tailwind
Bootstrap
Material UI

Sass
Firebase
Jasmine
Jest

TOOLS

GitTerminalGithubNetlify

Vercel
Slack
Linear
Discord

• Twitter • Zoom

PROJECTS

Personal Projects

- https://ihemz-cocktail.netlify.app
- https://ihemz-stripe.netlify.app
- https://ihemz-grocery.netlify.app

Collaborative Projects

- <u>https://streetrates.hng.tech</u>
- https://coverly.hng.tech
- https://newdcstech.com
- <u>https://umecarts.com</u>